Elias Rubin

17 West Mercer #3, Seattle, WA, 98119 erubin@princeton.edu | 907.230.8330

OBJECTIVE

I am a junior at Princeton University studying Astrophysics and pursuing a certificate in Statistics and Machine Learning. I am at my best and happiest when solving problems and am interested in an internship for the summer of 2016. I have a rigorous scientific and quantitative background as well as substantial research experience and am most interested in working in technology.

EDUCATION

PRINCETON UNIVERSITY

A.B, ASTROPHYSICS

Expected May 2017 | Princeton, NJ Certificate in Statistics and Machine Learning

Certificate in Applications of Computing

Coursework

Probability and Stochastic Systems
Computational Physics Seminar
General Computer Science
Cosmology
General Relativity
Stars and Star Formation
Research Methods in Astrophysics
Quantum Mechanics
Thermal Physics
Mechanics and Waves
Intermediate Swahili

WEST ANCHORAGE HS

Grad. May 2013 | Anchorage, AK SUMMA CUM LAUDE

National AP Scholar, National Merit Finalist

SAT: Critical Reading - 800, Writing - 800, Math - 760

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python

C

Java

Julia

SOFTWARE AND TOOLS

Unix and Mac OS X LaTeX Git

Microsoft Office

EXPERIENCE

PRINCETON UNIVERSITY DEPARTMENT OF ASTROPHYSICS

SUMMER RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

June 2015 - August 2015 | Princeton, NJ

- Worked with faculty and research staff to model radiation feedback effects in giant molecular clouds using massively parallel radiation hydrodynamics simulations on a variety of architectures.
- Added additional physics to and wrote new simulation code for the *Athena* MHD modeling software in C.
- Managed and analyzed large amounts of simulation data using Python.

ANCHORAGE JUNIOR NORDIC LEAGUE

COACH

January 2012 - March 2013 | Anchorage, AK

- Instructed children ages 6-9 in cross-country skiing.
- Independently managed a group of between four and twelve skiers with various levels of experience and fitness.

ACTIVITIES AND SERVICE

OUTDOOR ACTION PROGRAM | LEADER & TECHNICAL SKILLS TRAINER

2014 - Present | Princeton, NJ

- Led a multiday wilderness backpacking orientation trip for first-year students.
- Continued to serve as a peer resource to first-year students throughout the academic year.
- Taught underclassmen interested in becoming Outdoor Action leaders technical wilderness skills and Leave No Trace principles.
- Led refresher classes for Outdoor Action Leaders before their orientation trips.
- Contributed to development of technical skills and Leave No Trace curriculum.

SANS COMIC SKETCH COMEDY | WRITING DIRECTOR

2015 - Present | Princeton, NJ

- Cofounded a new sketch comedy group at Princeton.
- Wrote several sketches and helped other writers develop their material.
- Planned and executed long term strategy for the group.

MWENGE ENGLISH SCHOOL | ENGLISH TEACHER

June 2014 - August 2014 | Dar es Salaam, Tanzania

• Taught English in individual and group lessons to adult learners with varying levels of experience.